# **Tushar Sappal**

# Senior Site Reliability Engineer

India | +918510077660 | sappal.tushar@gmail.com

• tusharsappal.github.io • github.com/tusharsappal

### **Professional Summary**

Software professional with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry, having experience in cloud technologies like AWS and Azure. Skilled in Python, Agile Methodologies, Devops / Site Reliability Engineering Practices, Test Automation, Development. Strong engineering professional with a Master's Degree focused in Software Systems from Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani.

## Work experience

#### Senior Site Reliability Engineer

#### **VMWare**

- Leading the Site Reliability Engineering efforts on Monitoring, Logging, Upgrade, Incident Management, Feature Development etc. on our Kubernetes PAAS Solution
- Developing custom monitoring solutions for platform monitoring, uptime
- .Feature development, enhancements for the Kubernetes PAAS platform
- On Call activities, Incident management and Postmortem efforts for the platform
- Leading and owning Pre and Post Deployment Validation, automated testing efforts
- Leading One Click Deployment of PAAS Infrastructure, auto-remediation / repairing of Infrastructure.

Senior Software Engineer- Site Reliability Engineering / Devops

Myntra Designs Pvt Ltd.

- Lead and developed the culture of SRE within the Organisation, implemenation of Automated Incident Management across services
- Lead Migration of Compute and Storage Services from AWS onto Azure

Senior Member of Technical Staff - Site Reliability Engineering

2012 - 2018

2018 - 2018

2018 - Present

#### Adobe Systems

- Co-ordinating and Collaborating Multi Geo efforts across different SAAS product teams in Digital Marketing Business Unit
- Lead Post and Pre-Deployment automated testing for SAAS products of Digital Marketing Business Unit
- Lead and completely owned the Nightly Performance Automation framework for the Performance Engineering Team
- Managed Feature escalation from support / customers and driving the respective fixes.
- Ensuring Production Service availability with maximum uptime for SAAS products in Digital Marketing Business Unit.
- Defining service SLA / SLOs of services
- Lead development of tools, automation to facilitate production system uptime and achieving product SLA



**Skills** 

Site Reliability Engineering Practices / Devops

Kubernetes/Docker

Python

Amazon Web Services

Infrastructure Monitoring / Logging

- Lead and owned projects and tools for migrating infrastructure from the DC to Cloud Vendors
- System Monitoring, Infra and application monitoring / logging , Incident Management and resolution, Infra Capacity Management.
- Troubleshooting and triaging operational and application issues and fixing them within the defined SLA.
- Writing up control scripts for new processes, defining SOPs for services.
- Lead production upgrades / updates / patching efforts.
- Lead the creation and optimization of deployment / upgrade pipelines of products : A step towrads one click deployments

#### **Education**

Master of Technology, Software Systems Birla Institute of Technology, Pilani

2014 - 2016

2008 - 2012

Bachelor Of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering Dehradun Institute Of Technology

Created with 📅 VisualCV

